Andrei R. Rabon

Zamboanga City, Zamboanga del Sur, Philippines • +63 927-158-0043 andreirabon@gmail.com • GitHub • Portfolio

Summary

React-focused Frontend Web Developer with three years of Quality Assurance experience. Leveraging quality assurance background to build efficient and effective web applications.

Skills

Technical: Git, Figma, REST API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Jest, Axios, TanStack, Zod, Zustand, Jotai, Atlassian Jira, Project Management, and Personnel Administration.

Interests: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Python, Go, and Development Operations (DevOps).

Experience

1. AKA Software Inc. Zamboanga City

Lead Quality Assurance Tester

January 2022 – Present

- Ensured web application quality through comprehensive manual and automated testing with Playwright.
- Managed defects from identification to resolution, using Jira.
- Played a key role in pre-production testing, verifying new features and bug fixes for stable releases.
- 2. Philippine Statistics Authority RFO 9

Zamboanga City

Data Map Screener

August – October 2021

- Updated geotagged building structure data and geotagged economic data using QGIS.
- 3. Department of Agriculture RFO 9

Zamboanga City

Administrative Aide III

January – December 2020

- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap to create frontend web page drafts.
- Supported the ICT Planning Monitoring and Evaluation Division by handling administrative tasks (phone calls, emails, data entry) and providing technical support for computer hardware and software.
- 4. Department of Information and Communications Technology RFO 9

Zamboanga City

Internship

November 2018 – January 2019

• Assisted the Tech4Ed team with launching a new center and promoting the program through school and community outreach; supported the eBPLS team by preparing and facilitating seminars and workshops.

Education

Undergraduate: Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Pilar College

Zamboanga City, Zamboanga del Sur

2016 - 2019

Postgraduate: Master of Public Administration Major in Personnel Administration

Western Mindanao State University Zamboanga City, Zamboanga del Sur

2021 – 2024 (No diploma but with Complete Academic Records)